Guide to the William Stringfellow papers, 1940-1985
Stringfellow, William papers, 1940-1985
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
William Stringfellow papers, 1940-1985.
4438
William Stringfellow.
80.5 cubic ft.
Correspondence, newspaper articles and clippings, manuscripts, legal documents, flyers and tickets, scrapbooks, pamphlets, plaques, medals, yearbooks, cassette tapes, films, certificates, passports, posters, records.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Personal and professional effects of William Stringfellow, lawyer, theologian and social critic in Harlem, NY and Block Island, RI.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Lawyer, theologian, and social critic.
William Stringfellow was born in Johnston, Rhode Island on April 26, 1928. He received his higher education at Bates College, A.B., 1949, London School of Economics and Political Science, 1950, and Harvard Law School, LL.B., 1956; and served in the U.S. Army from 1952-1953 where he attained the rank of Sergeant First Class. He was very active in student Christian youth movements throughout this time. A lawyer in East Harlem from 1957 to 1967, he was a pioneer among the advocates of the war on poverty. In 1966, after a prolonged illness, he moved to Block Island, R.I. where he concentrated on ecclesiastical matters. He contributed regularly to theological and legal journals, was a guest lecturer at leading universities, law schools, and seminaries, and authored or co-authored at least fourteen books. He died on March 2, 1985.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
The William Stringfellow collection consists of correspondence, including letters to and from Stringfellow; legal business documents, including court records, legal documents, and some correspondence dealing with his law business; materials relating to Bishop Pike; manuscripts by Stringfellow; manuscripts by others; publications with articles by or about Stringfellow; Block Island material, including legal, political, and historical information; Anthony Towne (poet and author, co-author with Stringfellow, and joint owner of the house on Block Island); materials relating to circuses, a hobby of Stringfellow's; newspapers and clippings; other magazines; printed matter; and miscellaneous photographs, scrapbooks, medals, plaques, yearbooks, tapes, certificates, passports, film (Who Do You Kill?), posters, and records.
Also, "An Annotated Bibliography of the Works of William Stringfellow," by Paul D. West, 1990.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Stringfellow, William.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. General Correspondence
Boxes 1-25
Letters to and from Stringfellow
Series II. Bishop Pike
Box 26
Materials dealing with Death and Life of Bishop Pike
Series III. Legal Business
Boxes 27-29
Court records, legal documents, and some correspondence dealing with his law business
Series IV. Manuscripts by Stringfellow
Boxes 30-35
Series V. Manuscripts by others
Boxes 36-39
Series VI. Magazines with Articles by or about Stringfellow
Box 40
Series VII. Block Island
Boxes 41-43
Materials pertaining to Block Island-legal, political history. Stringfellow was a Warden on Block Island from 1976-1978.
Series VIII. Anthony Towne Material
Boxes 44-45
Poet and author; co-author with Stringfellow, and joint owner of the house on Block Island
Series IX. Circus Materials
Boxes 46-47
Magazines, flyers, tickets, etc.
Series X. Newspapers
Boxes 48-54
Mostly clippings, various newsprint publications
Series XI. Other Magazines
Boxes 55-63
Mostly theological ( Sojourners, Witness, Christianity and Crisis, Presbyterian Survey, The Christian Century) and legal ( Harvard Law, New York State Bar Bulletin, Notre Dame Lawyer) with a few popular ones ( Esquire, New Yorker and Time).
Series XII. Printed Matter
Boxes 64-73
Includes any miscellaneous printed matter such as pages from magazines (excluding newspapers), books, pamphlets, flyers etc. and includes Xerox and mimeograph copies
Series XIII. Miscellaneous
Boxes 74-80
Photographs, scrapbooks, medals, plaques, yearbooks, tapes, certificates, passports, film: Who Do You Kill?, posters, records
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Correspondence
  - 1940-1952 (Box 1)
  - 1953-1956 (Box 2)
  - 1957-1958 (Box 3)
  - 1959-1960 (Box 4)
  - 1960-1961 (Box 5)
  - 1962 (Box 6)
  - 1963 (Box 7)
  - 1964 (Box 8)
  - 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - 1965 (Box 10)
  - 1966 (Box 11)
  - 1966-1967 (Box 12)
  - 1967-1968 (Box 13)
  - 1969-1970 (Box 14)
  - 1970-1971 (Box 15)
  - 1971-1972 (Box 16)
  - 1973-1974 (Box 17)
  - 1974-1975 (Box 18)
  - 1975-1976 (Box 19)
  - 1976-1977 (Box 20)
  - 1978-1979 (Box 21)
  - 1979-1980 (Box 22)
  - 1980-1981 (Box 23)
  - 1982-1984 (Box 24)
  - 1984-1985 (Box 25)
  - Miscellaneous personal files (Box 25)
- Series II. Bishop Pike
  - Materials dealing with Death and Life of Bishop Pike (Box 26)
- Series III. Legal Business
  - Wendt and Monahan (Box 27)
  - Monahan (Box 28)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 29)
- Series IV. Stringfellow Manuscripts (Box 30-35)
- Series V. Manuscripts by Others (Box 36-39)
- Series VI. Publications with Articles by or about Stringfellow (Box 40)
- Series VII. Block Island Material (Box 41-43)
- Series VIII. Anthony Towne Material (Box 44-46)
- Series IX. Circus Materials (Box 46-47)
- Series X. Newspapers and Clippings (Box 48-54)
- Series XI. Other Magazines (Box 55-63)
- Series XII. Printed Materials (Box 64-73)
- Series XIII. Miscellaneous
  - Scrapbooks, 1944-1947 (Box 74)
  - Scrapbooks, 1947-1956 (Box 75)
  - Records, plaques and film (Box 76)
  - Certificates and photographs (Box 77)
  - Tapes, passports and memorabilia (Box 78)
  - Photographs and yearbooks (Box 79)
  - Posters, paintings, plaque (Box 80)
  - Postcards and commercial photographs (Box 81)